Guide to the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees: 1915-1985
5488 B
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
669 linear feet.
Correspondence, Rule books, Agreements, etc.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brotherhood of Railway, Airline, and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express, and Station Employees.
Subjects:
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States--Sources.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted. Please contact the Kheel Center Reference Archivist for access information.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
This forms a portion of collection #5488 B. The guide to the entire collection is available here.
Series I is arranged in 63 sub-series by Union file number.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. CONSTITUTION, GRAND LODGE
  - Sub-Series 200-0. Grand Lodge Laws
    - General, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General, 1951-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Grand Lodge Statutes Const., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Grand Lodge Statutes Const., 1947 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - General, 1925-1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 200-1. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Qualification of Delegates, 1921-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Qualification of Delegates, 1946-1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 200-2. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Reinstatements, 1953-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Feb. 20, 1953-59.
    - Reinstatements, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      1951-Feb. 19, 1953.
    - Reinstatements, 1941-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Reinstatements, 1926-1940 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Reinstatements, 1921-1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 200-3. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Withdrawals, 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      March 1956-59.
    - Withdrawals, 1920-1931 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Withdrawal Cards, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      June 1954-Feb. 1956.
    - Withdrawals, 1952-1954 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Sept. 1952-May 1954.
    - Withdrawals, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      1949-Aug. 1952.
    - Withdrawals, 1942-1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Withdrawals, 1932-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 200-4. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Waiving per capita tax, 1920-1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 200-5. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Waiving of secret work, 1920-1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 200-6. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Transfers, 1943-1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Transfers, 1933-1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Transfers, 1920-1932 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 200-7. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Construction, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      Nov. 1922.
  - Sub-Series 200-8. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Initiation Fee, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      Aug. 1951-57.
    - Initiation Fee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      June 6, 1951-Aug. 15, 1951.
    - Initiation Fee, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Feb. 1951-June 5, 1951.
    - Initiation Fee, 1949-1951 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      June 1949-Jan. 1951.
    - Fees and dues, 1921-1949 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      1921-May 1949.
  - Sub-Series 200-9. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Cards and stamps, 1933-1953 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Out of work stamps, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Out of work stamps, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Out of work stamps, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Out of work stamps, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sub-Series 200-10. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Affiliation of Lodge with central bodies, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 200-11. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Raffles, lotteries, and circulars, 1951-1959 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      1951-59.
    - Raffles, lotteries, and circulars, 1935-1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Circulars, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 200-12. Grand Lodge Laws
    - System Lodge, A.C.L., 1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      1921 June, 1
  - Sub-Series 200-13. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Election of Grand Lodge Officers, 1921-1959 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      1921-59.
  - Sub-Series 200-14. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Voting strength of Lodges, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Voting strength of Lodges/National Conventions, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Jan. 11, 1922.
  - Sub-Series 200-15. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Mileage and per diem attending Grand Lodge Convention, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Mileage and per diem attending Grand Lodge Convention, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      1928 March 17
  - Sub-Series 200-16. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Salaries of Grand Lodge Officers, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Feb. 7, 1922.
  - Sub-Series 200-18. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Dues, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      Oct. 1, 1952.
    - Dues, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      1956-Sept. 31, 1959.
    - Dues, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      Oct. 1951-55.
    - Dues, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      June 21, 1951-Sept. 1951.
    - Dues, 1933-1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      1933-June 20, 1951.
    - Dues, 1923-1932 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 200-19. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Resort to courts, 1939-1958 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Resort to civil courts, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      Dec. 8, 1926.
  - Sub-Series 200-20. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Referendum, 1924-1957 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Sub-Series 200-21. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Charges, 1928-1948 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Sub-Series 200-24. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Grand Lodge representation in System Board negotiations, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      1925 July 3
  - Sub-Series 200-25. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Waving Grand Lodge per capita tax account, extended sickness, or unavoidable unemployment (out of work stamps), 1935-1958 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Waiving per capita tax, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Jan. 28, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 200-26. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Article 14, Sec. 2, distribution of minutes-Board of Trustees, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Dec. 14, 1925.
  - Sub-Series 200-27. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Signing Membership cards, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      Dec. 16, 1930.
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Signing Membership cards, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      Jan. 5, 1926.
  - Sub-Series 200-28. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Per capita tax, 1926-1957 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Sub-Series 200-29. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Duties of Board of trustees, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      1928 March 6
  - Sub-Series 200-30. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Brotherhood Building Co.-Acquisition and maintenance, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Brotherhood Building Co., 1926 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      1926 June 19
  - Sub-Series 200-31. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Jurisdiction, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Brotherhood Bonding Department, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Nov. 23, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 200-32. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Grand Lodge seal, 1935-1948 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Grand Lodge Seal, 1926 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      1926 April 30
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Lay Members, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      Aug. 27, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 200-34. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Election of Delegates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Dec. 30, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 200-33. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1943-1948 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1951-1959 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1938-1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Soliciting Funds-Circulars and Publications-Prohibited, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Circulars (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Construction of Grand Lodge Laws. Circulars, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Jan. 25, 1928.
    - Soliciting funds (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 200-34. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Election of delegates and alternates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Election of delegates and alternates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1936-1946 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Election of delegates and alternates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Election of delegates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Election of delegates and alternates to Grand Lodge Convention, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Election of delegates to Grand Lodge Convention (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series 200-35. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Suspension for cause, 1926-1958 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sub-Series 200-36. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Amendments to, 1927-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 200-37. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Suspension of Lodge charters, 1930-1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Construction of suspension of Lodge charters, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Dec. 5, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 200-38. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Appeal to Grand Executive Council, 1925-1954 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sub-Series 200-39. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Death Benefit Department, 1932-1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Death Benefit Department, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Death Benefit Department, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      1930 June 14
    - Death Benefit Department, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      Dec. 17, 1927.
  - Sub-Series 200-40. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Functions of General Auditor, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sub-Series 200-41. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      1959 April
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Jan. 1959-March 1959.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      Sept. 1958-Dec. 1958.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1955-1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      April 1955-Aug. 1958.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      Feb. 1955-March 1955.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      Dec. 15, 1954-Jan. 1955.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Nov. 11, 1954-Dec. 14, 1954.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1951-1954 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      April 17, 1951-Nov. 10, 1954.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      March 16, 1951-April 16, 1951.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      Feb. 1951-March 15, 1951.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Dec. 21, 1950-Jan. 1951.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Nov. 15, 1950-Dec. 20, 1950.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1947-1950 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      March 7, 1947-Nov. 14,1950.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Jan. 21, 1947-March 6, 1947.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      1946-Jan. 20, 1947.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Jan 1915-Feb. 1915, 1943.
    - 200-41(B). Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Feb. 16, 1943-Oct. 1943.
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Representation to Grand Lodge Convention, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Dec. 19, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 200-43. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Official name of the Brotherhood, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      1930 May 7
  - Sub-Series 200-44. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Assessments, 1930-1957 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 200-45. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Proxy voting, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      Feb. 19, 1931.
  - Sub-Series 200-46. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Personnel of Committee on Legislation, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Sub-Series 200-47. Grand Lodge Laws
    - National legislative Committees, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 200-48. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Proposal to change form of organization, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Sept. 23, 1931.
  - Sub-Series 200-49. Grand Lodge Laws
    - State or provincial legislative Committees, 1932-1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 200-50. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Expenses of General Chairman attending national wage conferences, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      1932 April 15
  - Sub-Series 200-51. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Waiving dues by Lodges, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Waiving dues by Lodges, 1943-1951 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Waiving dues by local Lodges, 1935-1942 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Dues, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      Sept. 7, 1932.
  - Sub-Series 200-42. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Quarterly reports, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      Jan. 31, 1929.
  - Sub-Series 200-52. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Duties of legislative Committees, 1933-1957 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Sub-Series 200-53. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Consolidation Boards of adjustment, 1935-1958 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series 200-54. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1953-1959 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1955-1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1957-1959 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      June 1957-59.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Feb. 1956-May 1957.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      July 1955-Jan. 1956.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Jan. 1953-June 1955.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Dec. 1951-Dec. 1952.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1949-1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Nov. 1949-Nov. 1951.
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      May 1947-Oct. 1949.
  - Sub-Series 200-57. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Misappropriation of funds, 1936-1959 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Sub-Series 200-54. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Jurisdiction of Lodges, 1935-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      1935-April 1947.
  - Sub-Series 200-56. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Duties of finance Committee, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sub-Series 200-58. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Out of service and pensioned members, 1952-1958 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Out of service and pensioned members, 1935-1944 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Out of service and pensioned members, 1945-1951 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series 200-59. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Eligibility-legislative representatives, 1947-1959 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Sub-Series 200-60. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Brotherhood emblem, 1948-1954 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Sub-Series 200-61. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Grand Lodge, 1951-1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Sub-Series 200-62. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Duties and prerogatives of the Grand President, 1951-1956 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sub-Series 200-63. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Roberts rules of order, 1947-1956 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Sub-Series 200-64. Grand Lodge Laws
    - Subversive activities (Article 13, Sec. 12(a)) Grand Lodge constitution, 1954-1957 (Box 7, Folder 20)